

Andreas Klein
Agile Coach & Scrum Master

COLOGNE AREA, GERMANY / +49 173 8888 987 / ANDY@IXIS.IO / WWW.IXIS.IO

Figuring out how to get things done in larger Software Teams as a <u>certified Scrum Master</u>. I help Agencies and Companies to realize large scale projects with a focus on happy teams and effective processes. I also enable <u>Conferences</u> to share experiences.

Outside of the web, I'm a proud father of two beautiful children, a passionate freestyle skateboarder/snowboarder and I like the taste of good espresso.

If there is still time, I write on my personal blog http://ixis.io about things of the Internet.

My other Profiles on the web:



twitter.com/ixisio



github.com/ixisio



xing.com/andreas_klein156

Skills

- Certified Scrum Master
- Agile Coaching
- Scaling Scrum
- Change Management for Agile Software Development Teams
- Frontend Development and Consulting
- Workshops, Trainings and Coaching
- Product Ownership
- Kanban
- Continuous Improvement

Project Experience

Vaillant Group // Scrum Master

- Customer: Vaillant Group Business Services GmbH
- Role: Scrum Master of 2 Teams, Agile Coach
- Date: Jan 2017 present

http://www.vaillant-group.com

Toom Baumarkt // Cross Channel Platform

- Customer: Rewe Group, Fork GmbH
- · Role: Front-End Architect, Agile Coach
- Date: Apr 2016 December 2016
- Technologies: Scrum, ES6, React.js

https://www.toom.de/

Aktion Mensch // Accessibility Workshop, Training

• Customer: Aktion Mensch e.V., Trusted Shops GmbH

Role: Workshop SpeakerDate: August 2016

Topics: Accessibility

https://www.aktion-mensch.de/ http://www.trustedshops.de/

Billiger-Mietwagen.de // React Application

· Customer: Billiger-Mietwagen.de, SilverTours GmbH

Role: Front-End ArchitectDate: Jan 2016 - March 2016

Technologies: React.js

https://www.billiger-mietwagen.de/

Vaillant, Saunier Duval Brand Group // Websites

- Customer: Vaillant Group Business Services GmbH
- Role: Front-End Developer
- Date: July 2014 December 2015
- Technologies: "Component based Development", Grunt, Javascript (jQuery), SASS (CSS3), HTML5, Accessibility, Responsive Web Design

http://www.vaillant.de/ http://www.vaillant.com/ http://www.saunierduval.com/

Share A Camper // Website, Portal

- Customer: ShareACamper GmbH
- Role: Front-End Architect & Developer, UX-Designer
- Date: Juni August 2015
- Technologies: Grunt, Browserify, SASS, Material Design, Reponsive Design

https://www.shareacamper.com

MPS Public Solutions // Application

- Customer: MPS Public Solutions GmbHRole: Front-End Architect, Agile Coach
- Date: Mai Juli 2015
- Technologies: Coaching, Angular.js, Grunt, SASS, Scrum, Teams Processes & Workflows

http://www.mps-solutions.de/

Aktion Mensch // Accessibility Workshop, Training

- · Customer: Aktion Mensch e.V., Kuehlhaus AG
- Role: Workshop Speaker
- Date: Juli 2015
- Topics: Accessibility, Website Architecture

https://www.aktion-mensch.de/ http://www.kuehlhaus.com/

Stadt Hamburg (LGV) // Workshop, Training

- Customer: LGV HamburgRole: Workshop Speaker
- Date: April 2015
- Topics: Javascript, Backbone & Require.js, Grunt, SASS, HTML5, Accessibility, Scalability, Application Architecture

http://www.hamburg.de/

Vaillant Group // Corporate Website

- Customer: Vaillant Group Business Services GM
- Role: Front-End Developer
- Date: until 11.2014
- Technologies: "Component based Development", Grunt, Javascript (jQuery), SASS(CSS3), HTML5, Accessibility, Responsive Web Design

http://www.vaillant-group.com/

.. Ask me if you want to see the years 2009 to 2013.

Work Experience

2016 - present	Freelance Agile Coach & Scrum Master www.ixis.io
2009 - 2016	Freelance Front-End Developer www.ixis.io
2011 - 2014	Frontend Developer - nexum AG www.nexum.de
2010 - 2012	Freelance Web Developer - Haimspiel Media GmbH www.haimspiel-media.de
2010 - 2011	Freelance Web Developer - Merida2 GmbH www.merida2.de
2010 - 2012	PHP-Developer and Designer - CoreCMS (Open-Source)
2009 - 2011	Application Developer eLearning - German Sport University Cologne www.dshs-koeln.de

Education

2008 - 2011	Study of Physics - University of Cologne (until 2009) Magisterium
	Study of Sports and Performance - German Sport University Cologne Bachelor of Science
1998 - 2007	Comprehensive school, Willy-Brandt Cologne Graduation from high school
1994 - 1998	Primary School, PPS Cologne



Cologne, last updated 20 June 2017, Andreas Klein